charterworld.com 2019-06-30

# CharterWorld.com Privacy Policy - yacht charters boats worldwide.

### Introduction

**Welcome the CharterWorld LLP (CharterWorld) privacy notice.**

CharterWorld respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects to you.

**Contents:**

1. Important Information and Who We Are

2. The Data We Collect About You

3. How Is Your Personal Data Collected

4. How We Use Your Personal Data

5. Disclosures of Your Personal Data

6. International Transfers

7. Data Security

8. Data Retention

9. Your Legal Rights

10. Glossary

**1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE**

**Purpose of this privacy notice**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how CharterWorld collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website or our services, including any data you may provide through this website when you sign up to our newsletter, purchase a product or service or take part in a competition. This website is not intended for children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

**Controller**

The CharterWorld is or maybe made up of different legal entities. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of each member of the CharterWorld so when we mention " CharterWorld ", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in CharterWorld responsible for processing your data. CharterWorld is the controller and responsible for this website.

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPO using the details set out below.

**Contact details**

o Full name of legal entity: CharterWorld LLP

o Name or title of DPO: Maria Korotaeva

o Email address: maria @ CharterWorld.com

o Postal address: CharterWorld LLP, 85 Great Portland Street, London, United Kingdom, W1W 7LT 

o Telephone number: +44 207 193 7830

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

**Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes**

This version was last updated on 24 May 2018.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

**Third-party links**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

**2. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

**We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:**

o Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email, in person or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you join the CharterWorld VIP Membership Club or place a request for services with CharterWorld and includes circumstances in which you:

 apply for our products or services;

 create an account on our website;

 subscribe to our service or publications;

 request marketing to be sent to you;

 enter a competition, promotion or survey; or

 give us some feedback.

o Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using server logs, cookies and other similar technologies. Please [see our cookie policy](https://www.charterworld.com/index.html?sub=Cookie-Policy) for further details.

o Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:

 Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU.

 Identity and Contact Data from publicly availably sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.

**3. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

o Identity Data includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.

o Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.

o Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences

o Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.

o Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.

o Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to interact with or access this website.

o Profile Data includes your membership identification number, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.

o Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.

We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We may collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your yacht charter preferences that you supply as well as possibly other data like race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data).

We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**If you fail to provide personal data**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

**4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

1. Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you

2. Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

3. Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us or by unsubscribing.

**Purposes for which we will use your personal data**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity**

| 

**Type of data**

| 

**Lawful basis/bases for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To register you as a new member or customer

| 

1.                   (a) Identity

2.                   (b) Contact

| 

Performance of a contract with you  
  
To process and deliver your requests and orders including:

3.                   (a) Fulfilment of requests placed by you or on your behalf

4.                   (b) Manage payments, fees and charges

5.                   (c) Collect and recover money owed to us

| 

6.                   (a) Identity

7.                   (b) Contact

8.                   (c) Financial

9.                   (d) Transaction

10.               (e) Marketing and Communications

| 

11.               (a) Performance of a contract with you

12.               (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:

13.               (a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

14.               (b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| 

15.               (a) Identity

16.               (b) Contact

17.               (c) Profile

18.               (d) Marketing and Communications

| 

19.               (a) Performance of a contract with you

20.               (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

21.               (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey

| 

22.               (a) Identity

23.               (b) Contact

24.               (c) Profile

25.               (d) Usage

26.               (e) Marketing and Communications

| 

27.               (a) Performance of a contract with you

28.               (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)

| 

29.               (a) Identity

30.               (b) Contact

31.               c) Technical

| 

32.               (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)

33.               (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you

| 

34.               (a) Identity

35.               (b) Contact

36.               (c) Profile

37.               (d) Usage

38.               (e) Marketing and Communications

39.               (f) Technical

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences

| 

40.               (a) Technical

41.               (b) Usage

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you

| 

42.               (a) Identity

43.               (b) Contact

44.               (c) Technical

45.               (d) Usage

46.               (e) Profile

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising:

P **romotional offers from us**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or placed a request with us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**Third-party marketing**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with a company outside the CharterWorld for marketing purposes and we will request ongoing consent to use your data to contact you regarding updates via thrid party newsletter sending companies.

**Opting out**

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.

**Change of purpose**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**5. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

o Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.

o External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.

o Specific third parties such as CharterWorld franchise partners.

o Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

**6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We share your personal data within CharterWorld. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

Many of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

o We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.

o Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.

o Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

**7. DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**8. DATA RETENTION**

H **ow long will you use my personal data for?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. To find out more about these rights, please refer to paragraph 10 below:

o Request access to your personal data.

o Request correction of your personal data.

o Request erasure of your personal data.

o Object to processing of your personal data.

o Request restriction of processing your personal data.

o Request transfer of your personal data.

o Right to withdraw consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**10. GLOSSARY**

**Lawful Basis**

Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).

You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

**Third Parties**

**Internal Third Parties**

Companies other than CharterWorld acting as joint controllers or processors and who are based in the United States of America, the United Arab Emirates and Hong Kong and provide:

o services pursuant to the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.

o IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.

**External Third Parties**

o Franchise partners acting as joint controllers or processors who may provide services pursuant to the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.

o Service providers acting as processors based who provide IT and system administration services.

o Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.

o HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.

o G-Suite and Gmail email and document hosting services

o Pipedrive CRM

o ShareThis social media like aggregation

o Liquid Web Hosting

**Your Legal Rights  **

**You have the right to:**

Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

\-------------

When using the CharterWorld.com website there is no requirement to register or provide an email address to freely access our online yacht charter database and our articles on yacht chartering, boating and charter locations. 

In particular, during CharterWorld's online inquiry and reservation process you will be asked for and must enter contact information such as an email address and contact number. There may be certain other information requested about any needs you have or special requirements for your yacht charter. We also often receive important information from clients such as financial, family or health information. Any and all information that CharterWorld or CharterWorld's employees may collect about you is only used to help us identify yacht charter options for you as an individual client. The information is also used to streamline and individualize your yacht charter holiday by matching your personal needs and requirements. This information will remain privileged and confidential and it will not be shared with any other third parties, except where necessary to process your booking or enquiry in order to customize your yacht charter experience or as specified by you the client. When you submit your booking request to us you agree that we may use and transfer your personal information in this manner.

Upon request, CharterWorld will be happy to provide a list of any personal information held. Any request for information will be meet with strong verification requirements. To enquire as to the information held by CharterWorld and to obtain a summary of the type of information held please contact us [here](https://www.charterworld.com/index.html?sub=contact).

CHARTERWORLD is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy (together with any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

The CHARTERWORLD.com domain (this website) is owned and operated by BOATWORLD LIMITED, and licenced by CHARTERWORLD LLP, registered in England and Wales. Our registered office is 85 Great Portland Street, London, United Kingdom, W1W 7LT. 

INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU:

We may collect information from you online including the following ways:

1\. Through our use of Google Analytics cookies (please see the cookies section below);

2\. Through your CHARTERWORLD account;

3\. Through your request to receive news information or mailings;

4\. Through your contacting us with enquiries and comments.

If you take one of the steps mentioned above, we may collect and process personal information about you such as:

Your name, address, email address and other contact information;

Information you have provided;

Records of your correspondence with us, if you have contacted us;

Details of your visit to the website.

CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We reserve the right to vary this privacy policy from time to time. Such variations become effective on posting on this website.

CONTACT US

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy should be sent via the contact us form or in writing to: CHARTERWORLD, 85 Great Portland Street, London, United Kingdom, W1W 7LT.
